yep i'm still lonely
you're never alone in the nether when
there's these guys around i've come to
the conclusion that the upside down
needs a rule
it's a very simple rule and it's not
hard to follow just don't afk
if you afk
bad things happen the gas spawn
the piglen spawn and you can't always
guarantee that you're wearing golden
boots so the rule is simple
just be there but yes it is still
lonely i haven't had
anyone turn up to the upside down yet
my goal was to get a little bit of this
build done knowing how long this side
took i have a feeling i won't be able to
complete it but i might be able to start
it you know you send out the invites you
make the effort
and
nobody
turns up it gets
pretty lonely oh well put my tea in the
microwave
i'm stuck
no
so it looks like i'm destined to glide
alone in my solitary castle
and then upside down forever more so i'd
like to just sum up my experience of
being alone in the nether here and it's
pretty sad
[Music]
but we must not dwell on the fact that
we have no friends we must go out and
make the effort to bring friends
to our annoyingly far away place that
doesn't actually have a lot going on for
it
back to the overworld we go
you see i gave i gave scar an invite and
i thought he'd pop over i have seen him
online but he's still here look he's
he's actually just been using it as a
like a trash can he's just been dumping
loads of stuff in here
this will not do you know what i think
we need to we need to make a little
point here maybe we need to move the
invitation over to where he's working
which is
the big
dig
whoa
whoa whoa whoa
and it looks like wow oh wow he's
finished maybe we need to put the
invitation in his face
here so that he can't miss it this is
one impressive build oh my goodness is
even the detail makes it come alive look
at that is he is scar the next hermit
cribs should should we should we hear it
cribscar next he's dug all the way down
to bedrock
that is
dedication
i have an idea i think we're going to go
straight up here and we're going to
leave an invitation where hopefully he
won't see it and maybe we'll even make
it
upside down itself
[Laughter]
i don't think scar will mind if we add a
spot of light here
just a highlight
[Laughter]
and then
and then the invitation needs to go
underneath we'll just put invitation to
upside down we'll just rename a bunch of
paper
this is called
persistence
this is this is how it's done
if at first you don't succeed
keep annoying your friends until they
listen
i can't get over i can't get over this
[Laughter]
now who el who else did we invite i
think it was b dubs wasn't it it was b
dubs now i think i i i really do need
some more green heads if i'm going to
keep inviting people because i i don't
actually have many of them
i see two people online beef and zeddaff
and i have no idea where they are
in fact i don't oh he's right there oh
what an opportunity um i need to be in
the overworld beef beef
beef
i guess we'll try zeddaf
let's try and find zeddaf's base it
might be this
said f i don't know anyone else that'll
make such a strange portal is this his
base oh is that he's there
so same as last time
we set our spawn
said
behind you
come come closer
closer
kill me
why is there no hesitation from these
people
absolutely
everyone's been wait seems to be waiting
again
more
again do it again
how many how many heads we need
no oh he's just he just oh he's just
he's not stopping
he's just not stopping
oh he's just getting inventive now
if you would indulge me again i
i think that's probably that's probably
enough now that that's enough zed thank
you for your service wow i feel so much
better now
everyone on this server is so ready to
execute me
i can sleep well tonight my job here is
done
goodbye
he's taking the bed this is the second
time i've lost my boots i keep losing my
shoes
just leaving them around the house right
we've got the green heads we've got a
fair few we can reset the killed by
zeddaf thing just by placing them
and then mining them back and since
we're here we might as well check the
the backup box has been sold who bought
the backup box 220 diamonds that went
very quickly actually
oh my goodness oh my goodness
diamonds
lots of diamonds
oh my lots and lots of diamonds
holy moly lots and lots of diamonds oh
who is buying gravel wow i've been i've
been cleared out oh my
seriously the barge i'm telling you the
barge is the shop this season did we
sell any netherright gear
uh no
not even a little bit i'm guessing
people don't need these but if we sold
one backup box i reckon we could
potentially easily sell another we're
actually getting so many profits per day
we check that we're now into the diamond
block zone 37 diamond blocks from this
one i'm gonna make my own diamond throne
soon take over the shopping district
myself don't need this anymore actually
this is this could be a really good
opportunity i know how i could also get
scar's attention for some reason he
misses the green head hanging from his
giant drill
we could make a little tea party
in here
so in theory what we do is we edit the
way that the diamond throne looks
like this we take away the seating area
and i'm i'm willing to bet that he will
put it back to normal when he sees it
and then he's gonna discover
something new he opens it up and he's
greeted with
this
a little diamond party in the pile i've
even written some signs here for him i i
say chaps wouldn't it be lovely to live
in the upside down yes yes i quite agree
nothing like hanging with your friends
getting up upside down
i concur my fine yeoman we should stop
sitting on diamonds and go
if scar doesn't get the idea from this i
don't know what to do we could also hang
one from the ceiling so we seal this up
for for our dear friend scar to find and
now i've got four more green heads and
we're going to go and secure our
invitation to b-dubs as well oh finally
b-dubs base is probably it's one of the
biggest base in terms of like square
footage
but i honestly can never find this place
has he seen my invitation they're all
the gang's all here
they're all still here bee dubs
everyone's not seeing my
cry for help
no no no this just won't do let's
reconfigure this and do something
different
we're gonna go up
we're gonna stack them up circus style
place the heads
the final two
this should get his attention
pop in all the invitations he can't
ignore us forever he can't ignore all of
us wow every time i come here i see i
see that he's made some progress whoa
that looks like the temple of time from
the legend of zelda that's amazing
that is oh that is not even half a
building that's just the front hold on a
second you guys give me a really hard
time for not finishing the back of my
base and then b dubs comes and does
something like this
and we hear nothing about it this isn't
even five percent of a building i've got
a small hole in the back of my mansion
and i never hear the end of it to be
fair because this is just a backdrop it
doesn't it i'm only joking it really
doesn't need all of the terraining done
i think it looks amazing sim simply as a
backdrop i mean look at that you don't
oh it just vanished you don't need it
you can imagine the rest of it there
because it's just for the background but
i mean
majestic
absolutely amazing okay right let's go
back to the upside down i actually
brought a bunch of gray wool with me
because i want to start
trying to make it a bit more mob proof
especially inside the mansion itself hey
it's my season six mansion
because we've got some real work to do
i have decided
that
this this farm is not really good i
there are some piglets going in that's
fine but like look look at that look how
many mobs there are spawning inside
itself now they've absolutely just
stopped dead so look the farm is not
doing well because while i chose an area
that did have a large lava lake
the second that i actually built the
upside down mansion
this happened
you get loads and loads of occupied mob
spaces
essentially i didn't think this through
so now i've got to go through the rather
painful experience of mob proofing
everything
with carpets
and i probably should go and get some
better colors
to match little the inside doesn't
matter as much because most of this will
be covered up anyway but look at this
look it's mad how many piglens and
zombie piglens there are so if we do
this
it will actually make our farm better
but to be honest with you i've been
thinking about removing this farm which
to be honest with you isn't very big
and giving up and moving it above the
bedrock layer
but we'll decide that later we'll see
what happens once we've mob proofed and
spawn proofed everything so this might
be this might be a job for off-camera
green because i'm not sure i want to
listen to
rare
all the time i'm already out of carpet
and that was three stacks so what we are
going to do on camera while i think
about how i'm going to tackle that or
maybe when i do get some friends i'll
ask them to help me out
so what we are going to do today is work
on
the actual mansion itself there's only
one third left it's very painful to
build but i've actually set up all the
resources that i need i've got shulker
boxes of all the important stuff
and i think it's about time we got
cracking on this get it done
and then
i can actually start focusing on making
this
a more productive place rather than just
cute upside down mansion so
without further ado let's get into the
build
ow
time lapse mode let's go
[Music]
it was only an hour time lapse and
that's what i managed to make only
because i'm running very very low on
time to get this video done however
knowing how long the rest of that took
is probably a good thing that i stopped
a little bit early so the one
last piece of the puzzle to go
and we will be
done with this
build
finally
it's really really getting there i did
completely forget about the back so i'm
genuinely thinking of removing this farm
and creating some proper interior i
don't really know how to break bedrock
maybe we'll invite impulse and hello how
did you get in there
you've got yourself stuck so what i'm
thinking is we redesign this we get rid
of all of that send it up into the air
have the pig men fall
and then inside here is actually where
we create the piglin hall for trading
everyone seems to have one i'm not gonna
lie it's not gonna be unique but it
would make sense if i flattened off this
area and
remember that clip at the beginning of
the episode with all of the pain i went
through in the nether it's it's ongoing
it's never ending so yeah i'm definitely
feeling like reconfiguring and
redesigning everything here mob proofing
this because there's actually a lot of
space in here and in fact i might do
this for my real base
as well
hello
what have we got here
have we got
a little visitor that is a very little
house
it makes it does make it makes my
mansion look enormous
let's have a look who is this this has
got to be
either b-dubs or oh no don't panic i'm
here to save you so who do we think this
is
oh wow
there's torches hanging from the ceiling
except there
wait this messes with my head because
okay i get it that this is the ceiling
and the lights are hanging from it but
fire doesn't burn downwards like that is
really cool though okay so even the
interior is upside down i have no idea
who this belongs to
oh
there's some maybe we can try and
work out which one it is
based on the fact that there's only oh
there's a big gun with me get out of
here pork chop let's have a look and and
investigate that's not really telling
that could be the scar all b-dubs
ah okay this looks like a valuables box
i'm going to guess invitation b-dubs
it's b-dubs i was going to say that this
can't be scar because scar has a lot of
diamonds from his chest shop
so
i reckon this is beat up well we know
this is b-dubs and actually hold on he's
got his he's got his bed here now beds
beds explode in the nether quite
violently quite quite violently i think
we should initiate a
a rule that all new citizens of the
upside down must be pranked as a as an
initiation into our little group here
so i actually have a really i've just
thought of this on the spot i have a
really good way to prank b-dubs he's
only got a little house so this should
work what we're gonna do is we're gonna
put the bed down we're not gonna
interact with it
and we're just gonna leave it there okay
just leave the bed this is his own bed
he may even think that he placed this
himself we're gonna wait for b dubs to
get online
and then he's gonna come in here
and just
as he's hanging out i'm gonna pretend
like i'm in the overworld and i'm gonna
ask him
can anybody sleep
now i don't really know if he's gonna
fall for this maybe he'll remember he's
in the nether but b does is such like
instant sleeper all the time he may not
even think about it we'll find out i
can't i need him to get him right now
and he's put some la he's put ladders
here he's already changing the builds oh
right he probably came here for the
respawn anchor i'm just gonna check
around for my boots because i i've lost
them again it's not the end of the world
i've got plenty of netherright ingots
but this is like
maybe the third time i've lost my boots
oh oh b-dubs is here b-dubs is online
now's our time
we'll find the boots later i don't know
whether he's actually in the upside down
already i have no idea where he is so we
may we may be out of luck we may just
have to be very patient but let's not go
there straight away let's fly to the
back because we need
we need a good amount
of distance
oh he's there
oh he's right there let's get a bit
closer
what is he doing
okay so now what we do is we just wait
for him to get into the house
interact with something and then we ask
the question on the hermitcraft server
can anybody sleep is such a common
question and everyone knows what it's
like to be stuck outside at night in
minecraft so what is going on with his
eyes so it's like a common courtesy
thing if you can sleep if you're not in
the end or the nether or underground you
sleep if you can it's it's like an
unwritten hermitcraft rule if you can
sleep you sleep if someone asks i think
he's going in
i think he's going
he's he's
he's failing at flying again
there he is come on no no no come on
not even close b he's just given up he's
straight up given up okay now's our
chance
can anyone
sleep please
okay can anyone's oh yeah he's not there
what's he doing can anyone sleep please
oh
[Laughter]
he actually did it
oh no
oh no he had near the right stuff oh no
not good
not good not good in theory he should
have spawned up there right let's go
grab his stuff really quick in case it
despawns oh i'm crying i'm literally
crying oh his stuff is everywhere
thank goodness it was only a small house
and the other good thing about being the
netherright king is if he did lose
anything i can easily replace it
[Laughter]
he's trying to get back
he's trying he's trying to get back that
way
what's going on with his eyes thank you
for sleeping but you're welcome i was in
the nether i did that
you were oh
oh i didn't even put two or two together
you were here
oh
oh you did it on purpose oh
well i think here's what i'm thinking
welcome to the upside down we only have
thank you we used to have one rule we
now have two rules the first rule of the
upside down is don't afk it's too
dangerous trust me just don't do it and
rule number two
is all new citizens must be pranked and
i think you're the you're the first
person so
i'm the first
okay
oh that was a prank yeah you you sick
that was really smart
your eyes your eyes
oh sorry yeah yeah yeah i gotta relax
those uh
that you even cause i noticed i have my
green bed
you you put the same bed in it i took it
i saw it in your shulker box i was like
i'll usually use this real bad you oh
you sneaky that was brilliant okay okay
i'll give you that one i'll give you
that one thank goodness
it was only a small house but uh this is
i assumed that this wasn't going to be
your like main thing right this was just
a temp starter yeah yeah starter yeah
and it's basically rebuilt pretty much
yeah
it's pretty almost there okay so yeah
the other person i've invited is scar
and i haven't heard anything yet so i
did you see my you know steadily
increasing the invitations yes yes i did
yeah yeah i couldn't avoid it any longer
it was time
yeah good so i've also invited scar and
that means that rule number two when he
arrives we gotta prank him something
good
oh yes okay good it'll be nice to be on
the other end of this
yeah
he gets dude i was crying i was
literally crying
oh
i'm glad i brought you some joy with my
explosion i need to think of a prank
maybe you can come up with a prank as
well we'll we'll like you know confer
and then we'll we'll get him oh yeah
we'll get him good our audience this is
to our audiences
don't tell him if he knows it's coming
oh please don't tell me yeah yeah
secrets okay right anyway i'm gonna
continue with my my my stuff so i'll uh
i'll catch you later and i'm excited to
see what you do in the upside down
there's only two rules remember oh uh
and have fun it's gonna be okay i will
yeah you too
well we got an awful lot done today
we've actually got a guest and wow he's
prepared the house already we did a bit
of progress and overall we had a few
laughs now you may not see much progress
happen in the next few days because i am
actually away for a well-deserved break
in fact i'll probably be relaxing as you
see this video so
with that in mind i have definitely run
out of time for this episode and it may
be a couple of weeks or maybe one week
and maybe two who knows before you see
the next hermitcraft episode don't worry
it will be back and i have prepared
another video for while i'm away so all
there is left to say is thank you very
much for watching thank you very much
for your patience
and i'll see you in the next episode
good bye